It is that during the first 3-4 days, the oocyte that
you see here, is no longer called an oocyte, it is now referred to as a zygote.
But now there is something very important, because this is an algorithm that will repeat
all throughout development.
I asked you to remember one thing, to clearly understand the movements,
the notion of growth.
of developmental movements in growth.
Now, I will ask you to fully grasp this process.
So we have another image of polarity.
These first two cells of life will now divide
extremely quickly and more and more to form a bundle of
small cells.
But these first two life cells respond to a polarity,
which means they will not divide.
They do not divide at the same speed initially.
And the fact that they do not divide
at the same speed responds
again to the polarity.
Every time I have a cell division,
I have an increase in my membrane
and I have a loss of fluid outside.
I have a small exudate.
So, what will it do?
This will create
a mass of cells with,
alongside, in total,
a first small liquid cavity
that will appear.
And in
the beginning, during the first days, in fact, it multiplies, but the
whole
does not grow. So, for a certain time, since I have information about
multiplication
and a small loss of water, I have a global increase of my membrane and an increase
of my cells, in a confined space. What does that mean? It means that I have an increase
of my overall metabolism that increases, or in other words, I have an increase
of potential energy developing.
You didn't understand everything, I'll repeat.
At first,
you see the image,
I have my first two
life cells in a confined space
of a membrane called
the zona pellucida.
In there, I find myself
with the first two cells.
Both of them, what do they have?
We see that they each have
a nucleus inside.
Never
without...
They are always eccentric, contained within a plane.
Cell A and Cell B.
Well, depending on the polarity, one that is closer in its metabolic field,
will divide, thus dividing, a little faster
than the other.
We see that this will form this.
A bit faster.
Every time I have a division or a cellular cleavage, I
have an overall increase in the length of my membrane,
thus more exchange surface, and
an overall increase compared to this one.
And furthermore, I have an overall increase compared to this one.
on the side, an exudate, a bit of liquid that leaves,
that will collect here a little more than a bit
of liquid that appears. Now, I will show you a short film
that shows us this
asymmetric division, because if it were really as we see in the small
things
that we have always believed, at the same time, it doesn't happen
that way, it happens
In fact, it's just an expression of polarity.
What makes it go faster on one side than on the other?
It's not centered in the nucleus.
There is a nucleus that is not, even exactly, one that is closer to a metabolic field.
It's the one that will be closest to provide the metabolic field.
So here, we see these first cells.
And we will see here.
Hop, you see?
Okay.
and then the other will follow
later
and it’s never similar
this means that in the body
in life there is no
symmetry
but there exists
harmony
so at first
it’s not
the middle like that, I have two cells, it’s powerful, a capacity
for exchange, there are only two nuclei,
and then three cells, three nuclei, thus
more metabolic exchange force,
because if I take one cell and I place its nucleus here,
well here, this energy potential here, it’s a metabolic potential.
it’s an exchange force, ok, it’s powerful here, less
strong here, less strong here, much stronger here, okay, I will always
split like this, change, it's an important door, okay, now, imagine
that I am in the same space,
because for 3-4 days, the whole
divides more and more, but doesn't...
I don’t grow.
At some point, I divide and it’s as if, imagine, I
will mimic a power.
All of a sudden, it becomes internal like you have yourself.
A mass of metabolic energy ready to explode,
to come out, to search for new trophic forces.
At first, I have like an energy, a mass energy, a
potential energy building up, a metabolic power that gets
very, very strong, concentrating over three days.
That's a lot over three days.
I reach a sufficient concentration so that around the 3rd,
4th day to perform what is called hatching phenomenon.
This means that the cell that is enclosed, the whole is enclosed in tissue, all
of a sudden the force is sufficient to have a rupture
and I will leave into my fallopian tube to go towards
the implantation site.
At that moment, we have what we call the hatching phenomenon.
But just before this hatching phenomenon, in this
layer, what did I tell you?
Every time there is a cell division, there is a global increase in
the size of my membrane,
an increase in the number of cells, thus an increase in metabolism, an increase in force,
a power,
and furthermore, there is an exudate.
And the very first cavity that will appear, the water, what does it do?
It comes together, forming a small cavity here.
And what do we call this small cavity?
It's the first fluid cavity of the body.
But in fact, it will be called the blastocoel.
And typologically, what does it mean?
Blastocoel, the germ of the sky.
And you will see that this small cavity, we will see later,
of great importance
in the future cavity
coelom.
I will have what we call a hatching phenomenon.
At first, if I draw the first diagram,
I have many cells,
and I have a cavity,
and this cavity is always
eccentric. Why?
It is also an expression of a global polarity.
And the fact that there is this eccentric phenomenon will create a concentration
of cells at one pole,
called the animal pole and the vegetal pole, the assimilation pole.
A concentration of cells here.
Lots of cells.
And here, I have fewer.
First cavity here, you see, that appears.
It is a cellular exudate in a space,
here, and between this level and this level, there is
the hatching phenomenon.
This means that the membrane that is around here can no longer contain the thing.
Now, it’s too strong, there is a rupture, and we see that
there is a rupture here, and it starts to leave and come out.
The passage between this first cavity
with this exudate that forms the first cavity
called the blastocoel
will grow.
The difference between here and there
is that it's much larger.
Because I have
come out of the membrane.
Remember, initially, during 3 days
the embryo does not grow.
Well, the thing does not grow,
it always stays like that.
Except that inside,
there is a power.
And then,
at some point, the tissue surrounding me, there is a rupture, and hop, there is the hatching,
I leave my egg, somewhere, and I find myself in this external medium, and
in
this external medium, very quickly, I organize into a
concentrated zone of cells and a
And it's always the same image, it’s the blastocoel, but this time, which
is
going to become with what we call...
An embryonic pole, meaning a higher concentration of cells
on one side than the other.
And this pole, what is it? It is an assimilating pole.
Assimilate, it seeks to take in.